Siobhán Baines

Leeds, West Yorkshire
Telephone: 07766740070
Email: baines.smb@gmail.com
LinkedIn: Siobhan Baines

Profile

Junior Full Stack Developer with some proficiency in both frontend and backend development utilising HTML5, CSS3, Javascript and a particular interest in Python. Currently undertaking a Professional Diploma in Software Development to support the career change. Equipped with 30 years' experience in delivering a variety of solutions on the IBM AS400 platform and compatible API's. Troubleshooting and problem-solving skills are second nature as well as knowledge transfer, change management and requirements gathering. Experienced in ERP development and support, working with Relational Data, Application Programming, Interfaces and using a variety of programming languages and technologies. Analytical and methodical, staying current on the latest thinking and techniques and continually looking for improvement.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, GitHub, Python, Flask / Django Frameworks, MongoDB, Full Stack Frameworks, User Experience Design, Cloud Deployment, JavaScript, MySql, Bootstrap, Materialize

Packages: JDE World 7.3 & 9.4 (including AR, AP, GL, SOX, PO, SO), Data3

Programming Languages: RPGIII, RPGIV, RPGLE, CL, CLLE, AS400 query language

Applications: Create! Print, Bartender, Aldon, BizAgi, BRMS, MQ, IIB, Transform, Robot Scheduler, Showcase Query, Microsoft

Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Visio)

Transferable Expertise

Software Development: Determines operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements gathering, solution development and proposed solutions. Confer with testers and studying systems flow, data usage, and work processes.

Leadership: Self-reliant, strong critical decision making, motivating, team building, delegating and monitoring quality

Stakeholder Management: Forming, monitoring and maintaining constructive relationships by influencing stakeholders' expectations at all organisation levels, understanding their needs and delivering against agreed timescales

Project Management: Proficient at appropriate workflow management to ensure all work is prioritised and executed to meet

client needs

Analysis: Ability to identify systemic opportunities and implement detailed strategies to support effective transformative change. Implement set of practices and processes that lead to development of a set of well-formed business requirements from which the business solutions can be developed

Requirements Gathering: Expertise in utilising a variety of investigative techniques to elicit information from stakeholders and develop ways to manage their interests and expectations

Continuous Improvement: Proven ability to identify areas for further development, and able to support others in the process. Has an analytical and problem-solving approach to work. Excels at prioritising flexibly to meet rapidly changing needs. Adept at crisis and risk management

Key Skills

- Critical thinking
- Automation
- Developer in RPG on IBM AS400
- Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC)
- Process Improvement
- Risk analysis

- Applications Support
- Knowledge Transfer
- Attention to Detail
- Achieving strict deadlines
- Adaptable to change
- Accurate with attention to detail

Employment History

Dec 2020 to date Freelance Business Analyst - Baines SM Ltd

• Studying Diploma in Software Development with Code Institute

Mar 2020 – Dec 2020 Freelance Business Analyst - Baines SM Ltd/ Premier Farnell

- Collaborate with a variety of 3rd Party and internal, local and international stakeholders to enable successful implementation of new outsourced financial systems and produce FRS documentation.
- Demonstrated strong communication skills to liaise with stakeholders at all levels, including IT, Finance, IBM, Project Managers, Finance Directors, Business Owners and IT technicians
- Managed the delivery of numerous small projects, such as the redesign of the company's website emails and detailing requirements for a new invoice detail feed to a European government department

Oct 2019 – Jan 2020 Technology Lead – Infosys @ Hallmark Cards

Provided Application Support, identified requirements of projects as well as business and technical knowledge transfer

- Liaised with clients for project briefing, consultation, installation and closeout reviews
- Supervised activities between internal and external resources, and facilitated smooth workflow for service delivery

2016 – 2019 Business

Business Analyst/Senior JDE Support Technician - Hallmark Cards

- Collaborated with a variety of internal stakeholders to provide on-site support for the Japan office systems upgrade
- Served as Consultant across financial reporting, acted as liaison for Australian and Central Europe system upgrades
- Delivered complex knowledge transfer sessions to Infosys across multiple process areas, to facilitate take-on of services
- IBM MQ and IIB administration including dealing with external suppliers
- Supported the delivery of a new Pay-On-Scan process, modified a self-bill process to meet changing business requirements for major customers including Marks & Spencer and Morrisons. Held responsibility for the role-based security module and purchase order approvals process
- Simultaneously supported JDE World legacy 7.3 and current 9.4 systems, IBM MQ and IIB, and Robot Scheduler
- End-to-end management for the development deployment through Aldon LMi

2016 - 2019

IT Finance Stream Lead/JDE World Systems & Application Support Analyst - Hallmark Cards

- Pivotal member in the Hallmark strategic business transformation project which de-risked the legacy core system JDE World 7.3 to upgrade to vanilla JDE World 9.3.1
- Gained insights into the needs of the business by undertaking requirements gathering, As-Is and To-Be process flows, business specifications, technical specifications, system testing, 'hand-holding' testers throughout UAT, go-live data transfers and post go-live support
- Played a key role in the configuration of a self-bill invoicing and reconciliation model for the Marks & Spencer account, utilised expertise to provide technical guidance across the financial module, assisted in configuring the new to 9.3 rolebased security module, supporting legacy JDE 7.3 systems and managing multiple IBM AS400 systems operation tasks including the BRMS backup system

2006 - 2011

Analyst Programmer - Hallmark Cards

- Enhanced efficiency by liaising with the business, to gain an understanding of their needs; utilised influencing skills
 within meetings to set acceptable archiving criteria to reduce the amount of unnecessary data in JDE.
- Expanded the Ship Confirmation suite of programs to interface with SAP EWM; supported users by producing a technical user guide and created various labels in an antiquated BarTender system
- Liaised with stakeholders, developed and implemented a data archiving suite including a mechanism for data retrieval
- Developed and embedded interfaces to the Savoye LM7 warehousing system including the business-critical Ship Confirmation suite of programs
- Led projects including a project to increase the expiry year within JDE to ensure bespoke changes were compatible

Key Achievements:

- Successfully represented colleagues through TUPE and redundancy processes
- On-site Japanese go-live hyper-care support, JDE security and PO approval design
- First point of contact IBM MQ, IIB, Robot, Aldon, Showcase and role-based security when department was downsized

Jan 2005 - Dec 2006

Jul 2002 - Jan 2005

May 1990 - Jul 2002

Oct 1989 - Apr 1990

Sept 1987 - Oct 1989

Analyst Programmer - Baxter Healthcare

1st/2nd Line Support and Development Analysis Programmer - Jacuzzi UK

Analyst Programmer - William Hill Organization

Company Secretary and Contract Analyst Programmer - Hapwell Ltd

Analyst Programmer - Higham's Computer Services Ltd

Analyst Programmer - Baxter Healthcare

Education and Training

Full Stack Developer: Professional Diploma in Software Development – credit rated by Edinburgh Napier University Projects completed

- MS1 User Centric Frontend Development https://siobhanbaines.github.io/MS1-Portfolio/
- MS2 Interactive Frontend Development https://siobhanbaines.github.io/MS2-HP-Game/
- MS3 Data Centric Development https://our-family-favourites.herokuapp.com/
- MS4 Full Stack Frameworks with Django

BSc (Hons) Open (Strategy, Collaboration and Finance)

Professional Certificate in Accounting Diploma of Higher Education Open RPG 4 crossover & ILE

ITIL Foundation Certified

Certificate in Business Studies

AAT Level 2 Certificate for Accounting Technicians

Broker Administration

Introduction to Java and WebSphere IDE

Introduction to and Advanced RPG

TOPS training course

2 A' levels and 8 O' levels Inc Mathematics and English